Jao!
What?
[KARA] I just wanted to tell you,
wherever life takes you,
never forget
you’re a Siargaonon.
And you’ll always have a home here.
[QUINITO] Pearl, can we talk?
I’ve been meaning to tell you this, just to make it clear.
I like you a lot.
And just so there’s no confusion, I’d like to date you.
I’m just not ready to date anyone.
[ARIEL] Han Bin oppa!
Look. What’s the meaning of this?
[HAN BIN] If you don’t mind,
you can edit me out of the video.
- What? - Are you hiding something from us?
Jao’s in Cebu.
[CAROL] Just admit it already!
- You miss him! - I don’t!
Every time I say Jao’s name,
you smile.
[CAROL] See?
Ice candy!
Would you like an ice candy?
Coconut or mango?
Boat.
Boat?
Never mind. I just…
suddenly missed someone.
[JAO] Yes, sir?
You told me to take a vacation.
I’m good.
[PAUL ON THE PHONE] So, where are you?
Where I should be.
[JAO] Hi, miss.
Who are you calling “miss”?
I missed you, too.
[KARA SCOFFS]
Okay.
Why? Did I say something wrong?
I thought you were in Cebu?
Paul told me to...
take three weeks off.
Wait…
How did you know?
Tantan told us.
Well, he told me to take three weeks off, but...
Cebu just wasn’t my vibe.
Why not?
- Cebu is beautiful. - Yeah.
It’s beautiful and the food is good.
But it’s not Siargao.
And you're not there.
Got any plans tomorrow?
Nope.
Good.
[ALON BY JL]
[JAO] Can I ask you something?
[KARA] What?
[JAO] Why are you so guarded?
[JAO] I’ve felt that from the start.
No matter how warm and welcoming you are to others,
it always feels like there’s a wall I have to break through
to really get to know you.
[KARA] Really?
Sorry if I made you feel that way.
I guess it’s not deliberate.
I’ve just been badly hurt in the past.
So maybe I'm just being careful.
[JAO] With me?
[KARA] Not just with you.
Maybe in general.
About the people I let into my life...
The people I choose to trust...
The people I could love.
[JAO] Kara,
I still want to get to know you better.
Can you give me a chance?
[KARA] You can try.
But before you get to know me,
I think it’s time you meet Ruth.
Why did you buy me a burger?
Because you’re my friend.
Aw…
I’m not falling for that.
Are you here to accuse me of more crazy things?
Like what?
Like…
I don’t know!
Like, I’m a yoga teacher in India,
who can’t pronounce “namaste” correctly.
- Or... - Or you’re a Korean oppa…
who travels all around Asia
and falls in love with the Philippines,
falls in love with the island of Siargao,
and falls in love with my beautiful sister,
Pearl.
It’s okay!
I like you for Pearl.
I don’t know what you’re talking about.
Hey.
It’s okay.
I like you for Pearl. I know you will be good for her.
Really?
[ARIEL] Really!
[SIARGAONON] Really.
I know you’ll be good for her.
But I think…
Pearl wants to explore and experience the world.
Yeah, good for her.
But...
bad for me.
And I don’t think she likes me.
Han Bin oppa…
I know my sister.
I feel like she likes you.
[ARIEL] But she doesn’t realize it yet.
You know why? Because…
it’s your fault.
It’s because you don’t express your true feelings,
you’re always so serious around her.
But...
Pearl may not say much about it to me,
but I can tell
she’s dreaming of a life beyond this paradise.
I’ll tell you a story.
Our mother said that
when Pearl was five years old,
she met this Greek woman,
who was visiting the island.
And this Greek woman told Pearl
that she can taste all flavors of ice cream
and all kinds of chocolate in Europe.
And that’s when she started becoming curious.
Shallow, right?
No!
Not at all shallow.
Some childhood memories really stay with you.
And some memories even shape our future.
Hm. Says who?
Says a psychologist from…
Norway?
Says me.
A young boy from Seoul,
who dreamed of seeing the world
because my sister destroyed the globe my father gave me.
[HAN BIN SIGHS]
Pearl…
is just like me.
Chocolate and ice cream
represent a bigger world for her.
She must be smart.
She’s very smart.
Always so imaginative and
curious and asks so many questions.
So…
what should I do?
You know, Quinito is already close to her.
[ARIEL] You know why?
Because Quinito says what he feels.
He’s expressive, he’s proactive...
unlike you!
[HAN BIN] Then what do you want me to do?
Dance like Quinito like this?
- [ARIEL] Yeah! - Huh?
[SIARGAONON] You got the beat!
[SINGS IN SIARGAONON] You got the beat!
Yeah, you should dance like that.
- We’ll practice later. - [HAN BIN LAUGHS]
I’ll teach you.
Or do the aegyo.
Um, aegyo?
- [ARIEL] Yeah, aegyo! - Like how?
[JAO] Are these the mangroves?
[KARA] Yeah.
Ruth, Jao.
Jao, this is Ruth.
Ruth as in...
R-O-O-T?
As in “root”? Or…
Ruth as in R-U-T-H?
As in the name?
Boat!
[KARA AND JAO LAUGH]
Hi, Ruth! Nice to meet you.
I’m Jao.
I planted Ruth myself.
The mangroves helped a lot during Typhoon Odette.
They protected so many homes from the storm surge.
Ruth and all her kind are strong and resilient.
Mangroves really are essential to protecting Siargao, huh?
Yeah.
That’s why I hope…
there’ll be more mangroves across the Philippines.
Now that you’ve met Ruth,
you have to make her a promise.
Promise what?
Promise that...
you’ll protect her
and all her fellow mangroves.
Okay.
So, from this day,
I promise to help you
protect Ruth
and every mangrove here in Siargao.
Did you hear that Ruth?
She said thanks.
She did?
[KARA AND JAO CHUCKLE]
Ruth knows everything about me.
I whisper to her all my doubts,
fears, secrets.
Everything.
You should try talking to her, too.
What do I say?
[KARA] Anything! Tell her your secrets.
Huh?
Already?
Yes!
- I won’t listen. - Okay, okay.
[JAO WHISPERS INAUDIBLY]
[JAO] Okay.
Ruth is saying something, Kara.
Uh...
Okay.
She said I should tell you myself.
What is it?
I want more than friendship, Kara.
I want us to...
be more than what we are right now.
I want to get to know you more.
All of you.
Not to pressure you but…
to make you feel that you’re safe with me.
So,
if you’ll let me,
please let me in?
Jao, I’m hard to love.
Then why does this feel so easy?
I’m scared.
I fall too deeply.
I’m afraid the next time it happens, I’ll drown.
No, no, no…
Kara, we won’t rush anything.
Like what you said before…
"Just go with the flow and ride the waves."
I’ll ride it with you, Kara.
I’ll ride the waves with you.
And now that I’m here,
I won’t let you drown.
[HAN BIN] Hello!
- Hi! - Hi!
We have a reservation for two nights.
Okay, may I ask for the reservation name, please?
Yeah, it’s Ava Brooks.
Okay.
All right, I got it.
You know, you look like a K-pop star.
Me?
Um…
actually, I’ve heard that before,
but no.
It’s just the island air.
And you have a great smile.
- Yeah, it’s so white. - [HAN BIN CHUCKLES]
[GUEST] It’s so refreshing.
Thank you.
Okay. Um...
[HAN BIN] Uh...
Yes!
- Here we go. - Thank you.
Wait, is that your secret?
Yeah, actually, it’s kind of my secret.
It’s for maximum confidence.
Well, it’s working.
Are you single or taken?
Um...
I’m single
but my heart is already taken.
Aw!
She’s a lucky girl.
[HAN BIN CHUCKLES]
Okay.
So...
enjoy your stay.
Thank you!
[SIARGAONON] Thank you!
- [GUESTS] Thank you! - Thank you, guys!
[KARA] The key to good surfing is timing.
[JAO] You have to learn how to be one with the waves.
[KARA] If you get the timing right,
you can ride a good wave.
[JAO] But if you rush, you may not catch it.
You'll miss the wave...
and falling hurts.
[KARA] Is it the same as falling in love?
[JAO] Sometimes.
[JAO] But you have to take the risk.
Because when you get the chance
to ride out a good relationship,
it’s the best feeling in the world.
[JAO] I’m way rusty.
[KARA] Not at all!
But you know,
just give yourself more time back on the board,
and it’ll all come back to you.
[JAO] I really missed the waves in Siargao.
Maybe...
Uh...
I just need to keep surfing.
I’m sure I’ll get the feel for it again.
[WOMAN] Jao!
You know,
you two are more like people trying to make it work
than two people who naturally fit.
[HAN BIN] Jao! Join us.
[QUINITO] At least Jao...
always seems happy with Kara.
I’m just a happy guy.
What’s going on between you two?
You like Kara, don’t you?
Uh…
we just like spending a lot of time together.
- He’s blushing! - [HAN BIN] Look at him!
[QUINITO AND HAN BIN LAUGH]
[ARCHIE] Hi, Kara.
[KARA] Archie!
Long time!
When did you get back?
- [ARCHIE] I’ve missed you. - [KARA] I’ve missed you, too!
Jao, this is Archie.
Archie, this is Jao.
I’m Jao.
What do you do?
Uh… I’m on vacation,
so I’m not really interested to talk about work.